Research and the University Graduate School records, 1962-2003 C323
Indiana University Archives
Research and the University Graduate School records
1962-2003
1975-1999
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University, Bloomington. Research and the University Graduate School
C323
25.4 cubic feet 27 boxes
The Graduate School at Indiana University was founded, upon the recommendation of the Committee on Advanced Degrees, on February 1, 1904. For many years, a Research Committee handled the many graduate research funding requests until the 1977-1978 school year, when the Office of Research and Graduate Development (R&GD) was established to govern higher research at IU. In 1989, R&GD merged with the University Graduate School to become Research and the University Graduate School (RUGS). To lead this program, George Walker was appointed Dean of the Graduate School and Associate Vice President for Research. The merger combined the financial resources of the two offices while unloading some of the recordkeeping and admission duties onto the individual schools within the university. As a result, RUGS administrators were better able to work on cultivating financial resources and to study graduate student concerns. Prominent in the collection are records reflecting the heavy research mission of the university, such as the files on the many research centers and institutions, which comprises more than half of the collection.
Access Restrictions
Select files closed to researchers. These are indicated in the folder list. All restricted folders are housed in Boxes 25 and 26.
Advance notice is required for access.
Administrative History
Indiana University's Graduate School was founded, upon the recommendation of the Committee on Advanced Degrees, on February 1, 1904. The committee administered the School until 1908, when Carl H. Eigenmann was appointed as the first dean.
For many years, a university Research Committee handled the many research funding requests until the 1977-1978 school year when the Office of Research and Graduate Development (R&GD) was formed to govern higher level research at IU. The first dean of this office was Homer A. Neal, who served in this role until the 1980-1981 academic year, at which time George Springer became acting dean. Morton Lowengrub took over the position in 1982 and stayed through 1988. With Lowengrub's departure, Roger Farr became acting dean until 1989.
In 1989, the Office of Research and Graduate Development merged with the University Graduate School to become the Research and the University Graduate School (RUGS). To lead this program, George Walker was appointed Dean of the Graduate School and Associate Vice President for Research. The merger combined the financial resources of the two offices while unloading some of the recordkeeping and admission duties onto the individual schools within the university. As a result, RUGS administrators were better able to work on cultivating financial resources and to study graduate student concerns.
Dr. Walker retired as Vice President of Research in 2003 (but continued as Dean of the Graduate School while the university conducted a search for his successor), ending a tenure during which several new prominent centers and initiatives had been established at IU, such as the Center on Congress, the Center for Mathematical Education, and the Advanced Research and Technology Institute.
After Walker's retirement, RUGS split into two offices, the Office of the Vice President for Research and the University Graduate School. Vice President for Information Technology Michael A. McRobbie (later named the 18th president of the university), was asked to oversee this office and was given the additional title of Vice President for Research. Finally, in 2006, the office changed its name once more and became the Office of the Vice Provost for Research, led by P. Sarita Soni.
Arrangement
Organized into eleven series: Chronological files; RUGS files; Topical files; Academic schools; Academic departments; Administrative departments; RUGS committees; University centers; University centers, Proposed; University centers, Proposed, Not approved; and RUGS centers.
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the records in this collection span the tenures of Deans Lowengrub (1982-1988) and Walker (1989-2003).
The first series, Chronological files (1 cubic foot), spans the years from 2000 to 2003. It contains George Walker's outgoing correspondence arranged chronologically.
The second series, RUGS files (5.4 cubic feet), spans the period from 1973 to 2003 and is comprised of the general office files of RUGS, such as records pertaining to deans' meetings, presidential retreats, chancellor's notes, research compliance, and the Research Park.
Topical files make up the third series (1.3 cubic feet), spanning 1978-2000. Records within this series cover a variety of subjects, such as the Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC), Indianapolis Center for Advanced Research (ICFAR), the Lilly Endowment, and the Indiana Economic Development Council.
The fourth series, Academic schools (.6 cubic feet), spans the period from 1978-2000. Items in this series pertain to the interaction between RUGS and the many academic schools in which graduate students are enrolled, such as the College of Arts and Sciences and the School of Fine Arts.
Records in the fifth series, Academic departments (.3 cubic feet), are dated from 1985-1999. This small series relates to the relationship between RUGS and constituent departments such as Sociology and Psychology. Many times, these departments were involved in the organization of RUGS' centers and institutes.
The sixth series consists of RUGS' records on Administrative departments within the university, such as the Office of Affirmative Action and the Dean of the Faculties. Files regarding IU's regional campuses may also be found here. Records span the period from 1978-1999 and comprise .2 cubic feet.
The seventh series, RUGS committees (.1 cubic foot), is made up of only two files: Standing Committee on Research Integrity, 1996-1997 and University Research Policy Committee, 1997-1999.
The next series is titled University centers, 1978-2000 (1 cubic foot). These centers report to another school or office, but RUGS is responsible for making certain these centers are given confirmation of their center status as well as ensuring approval by the Board of Trustees.
The ninth series, University centers – Proposed (.6 cubic feet), spans the period from 1974-2000. Records pertaining to the Russian and East European Institute and the Rural Center for the Study and Prevention of HIV/STD can be found here.
The tenth series, University centers – Proposed – Not approved (.2 cubic feet), spans from the period from 1997-1999. Information regarding the Hamilton/Lugar Center and the Center for Underwater Science is included in this series.
The eleventh and final series, RUGS centers, 1962-2002, is the largest of this collection. Records in this series document those centers that report directly to RUGS. Prominent subjects include the Cyclotron Facility, the Institute for the Study of Developmental Disabilities (ISDD), the Kinsey Institute for Sex Research, and the Research Center for Language and Semiotic Studies. (13.7 cubic feet)
Separated Material
Personnel Action Recommendation forms and detailed financial records were pulled and shredded; unsuccessful finalist files from the 1999 presidential search and the unsuccessful candidate files from the 2002 presidential search for the Advanced Research and Technology Institute (ARTI) have also been pulled and shredded.
In addition, files dating from the time the office was known as the Office of the Vice President/Provost for Research have been separated and will be processed at a later date.
Acquisition Information
Accessions 3220-3222, 99/010, 2002/067, 2003/066, 2006/029, 2006/126
Education, Higher --Research --Indiana --Bloomington --History --20th century --Sources.; Education, Higher --Research --Indiana --Bloomington --History --21st century --Sources.; Research institutes --Indiana --Bloomington.; Universities and colleges --Indiana --Bloomington --Graduate work.; Indiana University, Bloomington. Office of Research and Graduate Development; Lowengrub, Morton, 1935- -- Correspondence; Indiana University, Bloomington. Research and the University Graduate School -- History -- Sources; Indiana University, Bloomington. Office of Research and Graduate Development -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Office of Research and Graduate Development -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University, Bloomington. Office of Research and Graduate Development -- History -- Sources; Walker, George E. -- Archives; Walker, George E. -- Correspondence; Lowengrub, Morton, 1935- -- Archives
- Chronological files, 2000-2003
  - January 2000 (Box 1)
  - February 2000 (Box 1)
  - March 2000 (Box 1)
  - April 2000 (Box 1)
  - May 2000 (Box 1)
  - June 2000 (Box 1)
  - July 2000 (Box 1)
  - August 2000 (Box 1)
  - September – October 2000 (Box 1)
  - November 2000 (Box 1)
  - December 2000 – February 2001 (Box 1)
  - March 2001 (Box 1)
  - April 2001 (Box 1)
  - May – June 2001 (Box 1)
  - July – August 2001 (Box 1)
  - September 2001 (Box 1)
  - October 2001 (Box 1)
  - November 2001 (Box 1)
  - December 2001 – January 2002 (Box 1)
  - February – March 2002 (Box 1)
  - April – May 2002 (Box 1)
  - June – July 2002 (Box 1)
  - August – September 2002 (Box 1)
  - October – November 2002 (Box 1)
  - December 2002 – February 2003 (Box 1)
  - March – April 2003 (Box 1)
- RUGS files, 1973-2003
  - Academic Deans Meetings (Box 2)
    - 1987-1994 (Box 2)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 2)
  - Assistant Vice President for Research (Box 2)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 2)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Associate Vice President for Research, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Biomedical Research Support Grants (BRSG) (Box 2)
    - Fall 1977 (Box 2)
    - 1978 (Box 2)
    - 1979 (Box 2)
    - 1980 (Box 2)
    - 1981 (Box 2)
    - 1982 (Box 2)
    - 1983 (Box 2)
    - Spring 1984 (Box 2)
    - Fall 1984 (Box 2)
    - 1985 (Box 2)
    - Spring 1986 (Box 2)
    - Fall 1986 (Box 2)
    - 1987 (Box 2)
    - 1988 (Box 2)
    - 1989 (Box 2)
    - Spring 1989 (Box 2)
    - Fall 1990 (Box 2)
    - Spring 1991 (Box 2)
    - Fall 1991 (Box 2)
    - Fall 1992 (Box 2)
    - Spring 1993 (Box 2)
    - Fall 1993 (Box 2)
    - Annual Reports (Box 2)
      - 1981 (Box 2)
      - 1982 (Box 2)
      - 1983 (Box 2)
      - 1984 (Box 2)
      - 1985 (Box 2)
      - 1986 (Box 2)
      - 1987 (Box 2)
      - 1988 (Box 2)
      - 1989 (Box 2)
      - 1990 (Box 2)
      - 1991 (Box 2)
      - 1992 (Box 2)
      - 1994 (Box 2)
    - Applications and Awards (Box 3)
      - 1977-1986 (Box 3)
      - 1987-1989 (Box 3)
      - 1990-1994 (Box 3)
    - Committee List, 1984-1992 (Box 3)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1983-1991 (Box 3)
  - Chancellor's Notes (Box 3)
    - 1991 (Box 3)
    - 1992 (Box 3)
    - 1992 (Box 3)
    - 1993 (Box 3)
    - 1994 (Box 3)
    - 1995-1999 (Box 3)
  - Circular A-110, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Contract Administration, 1996-1999 (Box 3)
  - Contracts, 1996-1999 (Box 3)
    - Expenditures, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Indirect Cost Income Reports (Box 3)
      - 1989-1999 (Box 3)
      - 1999 (Box 3)
  - Development, 1993-1999 (Box 3)
  - Distance Education, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Ethics, 1989-1997 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Research Fund, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - Federal Earmarks Project, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Gift Agreement, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - "Grantline" newsletter, 1987-1995 (Box 3a)
  - Institutional Research, 1993-1999 (Box 3)
  - Intellectual Property (Box 3)
    - January – April 1993 (Box 3)
    - 1993-1996 (Box 3)
    - 1996 (Box 3)
    - 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - Intercampus Awards (Box 3)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 3)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 3)
    - 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - Lilly Open Fellowships, 1984-1995 (Box 4)
  - Memoranda of Understanding, 1993-1995 (Box 4)
  - Minority Recruitment of Faculty, 1994-1997 (Box 4)
  - Packard Fellowship, 1994-1998 (Box 4)
  - President's Academic Planning Meeting, October 1989 – June 1991 (Box 4)
  - President's Advance (Box 4)
    - August 1995 (Box 4)
    - 1996-2000 (Box 4)
    - August 2001 (Box 4)
    - August 2002 (Box 4)
  - President's Advance (Box 4)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 4)
    - 1994 (Box 4)
  - President's Planning Work Group Report Document, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Research and Creative Activity (RCA) (Box 4)
    - 1993-1995 (Box 4)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 4)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Research Collaboration Initiative, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Research Compliance (Box 4)
    - 1990-1993 (Box 4)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 4)
    - 1997-1999 (Box 4)
    - Academic Misconduct (Box 4)
      General
      RESTRICTED
      - 1991-1995 (Box 4)
      - 1995-1997 (Box 4)
      - ca. 1995-1999 (Box 4)
    - Animals (Box 5)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 5)
      - 1997-2000 (Box 5)
    - Association of American Universities (AAU) Copyright, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Biosafety, 1990-1998 (Box 5)
    - Conflict of Interest, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
    - Human Subjects (Box 5)
      - 1990-1995 (Box 5)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 5)
      - 1998-1999 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992-1994 (Box 5)
    - Updates, 1993-1995 (Box 5)
  - Research Incentive Program, 1975-1994 (Box 5)
  - Research Leave – Supplement Policy, 1995-1999 (Box 5)
  - Research Park (Box 5)
    - 1982-1993 (Box 5)
    - 1992 (Box 5)
    - 1994 (Box 5)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 5)
    - 1996-2003 (Box 5)
  - Research Priorities, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
  - Research Ranks, 1976-1988 (Box 5)
  - Research Summaries, 1979-1988 (Box 5)
  - Research Summaries, 1979-1988 (Box 5)
    - Annual Report (Box 5)
      - 1975-1980 (Box 5)
      - 1980-1985 (Box 5)
      - 1986-1996 (Box 5)
    - Associate Dean Search (Box 5)
      - Advertising, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
      - Affirmative Action, 1998-1999 (Box 5)
      - Committee Roster, 1997 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 5)
      - Interview Arrangements, 1998 (Box 5)
      - Job Description, 1998 (Box 5)
      - Letters to Applicants, 1998 (Box 5)
      - Mailings, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Deans' Meetings (Box 5)
      - 1980-1983 (Box 5)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 5)
      - 1986-1992 (Box 5)
    - Deans' Retreat, 1986-1992 (Box 6)
    - Ehrlich Charges, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    - Memos (Box 6)
      - 1973-1976 (Box 6)
      - 1977-1984 (Box 6)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 6)
      - 1987-1999 (Box 6)
    - Review (Box 6)
      - Committee Material, 1993; (2 folders) (Box 6)
      - RUGS Deans and Staff, 1981 (Box 6)
      - Supplementary Material, 1993; (2 folders) (Box 6)
      - Walker, George (Director) (Box 6)
        - 1993-1994 (Box 6)
        - 1997-1998 (Box 6)
        - 1998 (Box 6)
    - Space, 1978-1983 (Box 6)
    - Staff Directories, 1989-1999 (Box 6)
  - Scholarship of Teaching and Learning, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Social Science Initiative (Box 6)
    - 1993 (Box 6)
    - 1994-1998 (Box 6)
  - Sponsored Research Services (Box 6)
    - General (Box 6)
      - 1994-August 1995 (Box 6)
      - 1995-May 1997 (Box 6)
      - June 1997-September 1998 (Box 6)
      - October 1998-1999 (Box 6)
    - Institutional Nominations, 1998-1999 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1997 (Box 6)
    - Reports (Box 6)
      - 1987-1992 (Box 6)
      - 1990-January 1994 (Box 6)
      - February 1994-1995 (Box 7)
    - Teleconference (Box 7)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 7)
      - 1993-1996 (Box 7)
  - Start-Up Funds, 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Strategic Directions Charter (Box 7)
    - Josh Powers Analysis, 1996-1998 (Box 7)
    - Plan, 1995-1997 (Box 7)
    - Process, 1995-1999 (Box 7)
    - Publicity and Reports, 1995-1997 (Box 7)
    - Round 1 (Box 7)
      - Awards, 1996 (Box 7)
      - Panel (Box 7)
        - Alberts: "The Responsibility of Excellence", 1996 (Box 7)
        - Farr: "Accountability and Best Practices", 1996 (Box 7)
        - Kintgen: "The Community of Learning", 1996 (Box 7)
      - Reports, 1995-1996 (Box 7)
    - Round 2 (Box 7)
      - Awards, 1997 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous, 1996 (Box 7)
      - Panels, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Round 3 (Box 7)
      - Awards, 1998 (Box 7)
      - Not Awarded, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Surveys, 1990-1999 (Box 7)
  - Trustees Meetings (Box 7)
    - June 23, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Grad Fees, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Trustees Presentations (Box 7)
    - 1989-1994 (Box 7)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Trustees Reports, 2000-2002 (Box 7)
  - Twenty-First Century Fund, 1998-1999; (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Vice President for Information Technology (VPIT) Search (Box 7)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 7)
    - McRobbie, Michael, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Position Description, 1995 (Box 7)
- Topical files, 1978-2000
  - Alliance of Distinguished Rank Professors, 1993-1998 (Box 7)
  - American Advancement for the Advancement of Science, 1996-1998 (Box 7)
  - American Association of University Professors (AAUP), 1997 (Box 7)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU) Reports, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Bloomington Economic Development Corp., 1995-1997 (Box 8)
  - Coalition for National Science Funding (Box 8)
    - 1999 (Box 8)
    - Exhibition, 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC) (Box 8)
    - Publications, 1993-1998 (Box 8)
    - Research Officers, 1994-1998 (Box 8)
  - Crane, 1995-1998 (Box 8)
  - Health Industry Forum, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Indiana Economic Development Council, 1986-1993 (Box 8)
  - Indiana University Advanced Research and Technology Institute (IU ARTI (now IU RTC)) (Box 8)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 8)
  - Indianapolis Center for Advanced Research (ICFAR) (Box 8)
    - 1988-1995 (Box 8)
    - Board of Director's Meeting (Box 8)
      - June 20, 1990 (Box 8)
      - October 17, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Japanese-American Consortium for Exchange of Scholars (JACES) (Box 8)
    - 1994, (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 1995 (Box 8)
  - Lilly Endowment, 1994-1999 (Box 8)
  - National Research Council, 1992-1999 (Box 8)
  - North Central Association (Box 8)
    - 1986-1999 (Box 8)
    - Self-Study, 1984-1997 (Box 8)
  - Organization for Topical Studies, 1996-1999 (Box 8)
  - Research Center for Language and Semiotic Studies (RCLSS) Publications (Box 8)
    - 1978-1990 (Box 8)
    - 1993-1998 (Box 8)
  - Sebeok, Thomas – Personal (Box 8)
    - 1985 (Box 8)
    - 1986-1999 (Box 8)
  - Semiotics Publications (Box 9)
    - 1982-1990 (Box 9)
    - 1990-1999 (Box 9)
  - Walden University, 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - WIN (Wisconsin, Indiana, NOAO) Telescope Project, 1987-1988 (Box 9)
  - WIYN (Wisconsin, Indiana, Yale, NOAO) Observatory, 1985-1994 (Box 9)
  - Wonderlab, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
- Academic schools, 1978-2000
  - Arts and Sciences, College of, 1994-1999 (Box 9)
  - Business, 1994-1999 (Box 9)
  - Continuing Education, 1978-1996 (Box 9)
  - Education (Box 9)
    - 1993-1999 (Box 9)
    - Wisdom Tools, 1995-2000 (Box 9)
  - Fine Arts, 1982-1999 (Box 9)
  - Health, Physical Education and Recreation (HPER), 1993-1999 (Box 9)
  - Informatics (Box 9)
    - 1999 (Box 9)
    - Information Technology Working Group, 1999-circa 2000 (Box 9)
  - Journalism, 1982-1996 (Box 9)
  - Law, 1990-1997 (Box 9)
  - Library and Information Science, 1990-1997 (Box 9)
  - Medicine, 1992-1999 (Box 9)
  - Music, 1987-1999 (Box 9)
  - Optometry, 1989-1999 (Box 9)
  - Social Work, 1992-1998 (Box 9)
  - School of Public and Environmental Affairs (SPEA) (Box 9)
    - 1989-1998 (Box 9)
    - Review Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 9)
- Academic departments, 1985-1999
  - Afro-American Studies, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Biology (Box 9)
    - 1999 (Box 9)
    - Medical Sciences Review, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Political Science, 1989-1996 (Box 9)
  - Psychology (Box 9)
    - 1988-1999 (Box 9)
    - Cognitive Science Program, 1987-1999 (Box 10)
    - Neuroscience Center, 1985-1990 (Box 10)
  - Radio and TV, 1993-1999 (Box 10)
  - Religious Studies, 1990-1997 (Box 10)
  - Slavic Literature and Language (Box 10)
    - 1991-1999 (Box 10)
    - Slavica Publishers, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
  - Sociology, 1989-1998 (Box 10)
  - Spanish and Portuguese, 1991-1998 (Box 10)
  - Speech and Hearing, 1989-1999 (Box 10)
  - Telecommunications, 1986-1993 (Box 10)
  - Theatre and Drama, 1990-1998 (Box 10)
  - Uralic and Altaic Studies, 1989-1994 (Box 10)
  - Victorian Studies, 1996 (Box 10)
  - West European Studies, 1988-1997 (Box 10)
- Administrative departments, 1978-1999
  - Affirmative Action, circa 1997 (Box 10)
  - Afro-American Affairs, 1992-1999 (Box 10)
  - Alumni Office, 1995-1997 (Box 10)
  - Archives, 1978; 1997 (Box 10)
  - Faculties, Dean of, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Federal Relations, 1995-1999 (Box 10)
  - Indiana University East (IUE) at Richmond, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Indiana University Foundation, 1993-1999 (Box 10)
  - Indiana University Kokomo (IUK), 1999 (Box 10)
  - Indiana University Press, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Indiana University Purdue University Indianapolis (IUPUI) Chancellor Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 10)
  - International Programs, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - La Caixa, 1994 (Box 10)
  - President's Office, 1997-1999 (Box 10)
  - State Relations, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Vice President of Administration – Clapacs, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Vice President for Diversity – Nelms, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Vice President for Information Technology (VPIT) – McRobbie, 1999 (Box 10)
- RUGS committees, 1996-1999
  - Standing Committee on Research Integrity, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
  - University Research Policy Committee, 1997-1999 (Box 10)
- University centers, 1978-2000
  - Archives of Traditional Music, 1978-1990 (Box 10)
  - Borish Center for Ophthalmic Research (Box 10)
    - circa 1995, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - 1995-1998 (Box 10)
  - Center for Earth and Environmental Science, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
  - Center for Education and Research in Retailing, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Center for Entrepreneurship and Innovation, 1990-1993 (Box 10)
  - Center for Geospatial Data Analysis, 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Center for Hearing Aid Research and Technical Training, 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Center for the History of Music Theory and Literature, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Center for Innovation in Assessment, 1997-1999 (Box 10)
  - Center for Innovative Computing Applications, 1990-1991 (Box 10)
  - Center for Integrative Study of Animal Behavior (Box 10)
    - 1989-1999 (Box 10)
    - 1995-2000 (Box 11)
  - Center for Latin American and Caribbean Studies, 1978-1989 (Box 11)
  - Center for Research on Learning and Technology, 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Center for the Study of Law and Society, 1988-1993 (Box 11)
  - Center on Aging and the Aged (Box 11)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 11)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Center on Philanthropy, 1987-1994 (Box 11)
  - Center on Southeast Asia, 1994-1996 (Box 11)
  - Center for Urban Policy and the Environment at IUPUI, 1992-1997 (Box 11)
  - Committee for Research and Development in Language Instruction (CREDLI), 1980-1997 (Box 11)
  - Eppley Institute, 1993-1994 (Box 11)
  - Indiana Center for Global Business, 1989-1993 (Box 11)
  - Indiana Center for Global Change and World Peace, 1989-1994 (Box 11)
  - Indiana Center for Intercultural Communication, 1999 (Box 11)
  - Interdisciplinary Consortium for Statistical Applications (Box 11)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - 1990-1998 (Box 11)
- University centers – Proposed, 1974-2000
  - Indiana Education Policy Center (Box 11)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - 1991-2000 (Box 11)
  - Institute for Forensic Imaging, 1997-1998 (Box 11)
  - International Development Institute (IDI), 1974-1991 (Box 11)
  - Leisure Research Institute, 1990-1992 (Box 11)
  - Living Learning Center, 1980-1999 (Box 11)
  - Midwest Center – Institute for Global Environmental Change (Box 11)
    - 1990 (Box 11)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - 1992-1999 (Box 11)
  - Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Center (IUPUI), 1992 (Box 11)
  - Peirce Project, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Renaissance Studies, 1987-1994 (Box 11)